Nigel David

Residence: Austin, TX

Email: nigel.a.david@gmail.com

PROFILE

Nigel David is a Web Developer in IBM's Global Business Services organization. He is an adaptable, organized, and detail oriented software engineer. His background comes from his degree in computer science and positions as a web developer. He has recent experience as a scrum master, system engineer, and developer for AT&T telecommunication software.

EXPERIENCE

IBM

October 2013 - Present

Software Defined Networks – GUI Portal, AT&T Account Developer

April 2016 – Present

Created and enhanced components of AT&T's SDN Web Portal. Coded the front end components using HTML, JS, and the DHTMLX (JS, AJAX, HTML) framework which presented the user with a functional GUI. Coded the back end components were Java and Spring which were used for data processing and REST API handling. The system ran MariaDb to maintain customer provisioning data. Ran Fortify Scan and fixed security vulnerabilities. Wrote backend unit tests using JUnit and Mockito.

<u>Tools Used:</u> Websphere, SVN, XMLSpy, MySQL Workbench, Eclipse, CA Agile, Rational Team Concert, Bitbucket, Git, JIRA, Tomcat, Maven,

AT&T Account Scrum Master

June 2014 - March 2016

Served as a leader for scrum teams to ensure Agile methodologies and principles are adhered to throughout iterations, prevent interference from outside the Scrum team, and provide assistance to the team when potential blockers are present. Organize and facilitate sprint planning, daily stand-up meetings, reviews, retrospectives, release planning, demos and other Scrum related meetings. Coordinate deliverables across iterations and releases and act as a liaison between the Product Owners and the team.

Universal Service Request Platform, AT&T System Engineer

October 2013 - June 2015

Created system requirements and documentation that represents the customer's vision for AT&T's Universal Service Request Platform. Used logical data analysis and design principles to coordinate requirements with developers and other engineers to enhance and maintain the system.

Tools used: Word, Excel macros, VI, Eclipse, XML Spy, iRise, Sybase, ReqPro, RallyDev

Texas State University

August 2010 – July 2013

Office of Educator Preparation Web Master

October 2012 - July 2013

Created research dashboards and displays using LogiXML (similar to Cognos). Managed the department website using a CMS, CSS, and JavaScript. Developed web applications to support the staff's needs using HTML, jQuery, and AJAX.

Office of the Associate Vice President for Research Web Master

January 2011 – October 2012

Manually imported curriculum vitae into research profile database. Consolidated MySQL database. Developed web applications in a LAMP environment. Created application forms for research funding using HTML, PHP, and JavaScript. Managed the department website using GATO (a content manager), CSS, and JavaScript.

IT Assistance Center Technical Support Representative

August 2010 – November 2010

Helped students, teachers and faculty solve internet related issues. Explained complex problems in a simple manner. Contributed to the knowledge base for troubleshooting.

Telenetwork

Technical Support Representative

August 2009 - May 2010

Helped customers solve internet related issues. Explained complex problems in a simple manner while being courteous. Explain procedure and policies to the customers.

EDUCATION

Texas State University,

August 2008 - May 2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Minor in Applied Mathematics

Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, Networks, Parallel Programming, Human Factors, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Architecture, and fundamental programming courses

SKILLS

- Scrum Master Experience on Agile and Blended Agile projects
- Skilled with design document creation and technical writing
- Practiced System Engineer providing maintenance services for software

- Telecommunications Industry Experience with AT&T ordering and provisioning systems
- Skilled with the MS Office Suite: Word, Excel, Visio, PowerPoint
- Experienced with building web applications with the LAMP stack
- Intermediate skill with C, C++, Java, JS
- Basic skill with CUDA, AngularJS, PHP
- Basic knowledge of architecture exploitations, parallel approaches and optimizations
- Knowledge of database constructs, schema design, and SQL
- Skilled at managing, maintaining, troubleshooting, installing and configuring customer end network equipment
- Trained in troubleshooting PC and Mac issues
- Effective communication in a business and technical environment